Anjesh Ghimire

JavaScript Developer · MERN Stack

GatthaGhar, Bhaktapur

9824035436 | anjesh67890@gmail.com

Summary

JavaScript developer (MERN stack) who is passionate about developing the websites using MERN stack, and love to contribute to tech community by sharing experience and knowledge. I have worked on various projects by using JavaScript and its framework and libraries.

Love to contribute tech communities by sharing knowledge and experience. Always trying to customize to find the most optimal environment. Interested in devising a better problem-solving method for challenging tasks, and learning new technologies and tools.

Work Experience_

GreenCodes Nepal (Pepsicola, Kathmandu)

Oct.2020-Sep 2023

JavaScript Developer

- · Currently using JavaScript, Typescript, CSS, HTML, BootStrap, and SASS to create a component for the website creation from various clients.
- Developed a modern UI using CSS flexbox, grid, and JavaScript.
- Responsible for developing the full flexed website using MERN stack, and using concepts like API calls, Middleware, Interceptors, Authentication, Authorizations, Request headers, Response, tokens, and handling response in Frontend.
- Used a version control system GitHub for managing all the changes to a code.
- Have an experience with NodeJs, and more preferably Express Js, and consume Restful APIs using various tools and libraries, such as Axios, Mongoose, Passport, bcryptJs, expressAsyncHandler, JSONwebToken
- Have an excellent problem-solving skills and analytical skills, and debug and test the code using Chrome DevTools, Postman, and familiar with JIRA.

Midas Technologies Pvt. Ltd. (Panipokhari, IME complex)

Oct. 2023 -Present

JavaScript Developer

- Developed and maintained front-end code for multiple projects, ensuring cross-browser compatibility and optimal performance.
- Actively participated in code reviews
- Stayed updated with frontend technologies trends, tools and best practices
- · Used Company own PMS system for project management, Ant Design, Tailwind, React Hooks, Web pack, CSS, HTML

Independence Freelance (United Kingdom)

Oct 2022-Mar 2023

- Implemented RESTful API server for Morito Suppliers
- Developed a full flexed E-commerce website for a client from U.K using MERN Stack.

Personal Projects_

Company Website

GREENCODES NEPAL

• Website of company that includes all the functionality for hiring process , cv upload and company descriptions and so on (MERN STACK)

Job Portal Website

Gold Tree

· Website which is in development phase which includes all the functionality of job search.(MERN STACK)

Education₋

K.U(Kathmandu University)

B.Sc. in COMPUTER Science AND Engineering

Dhulikhel, Kavre

July. 2017 - Aug. 2020

Skills

JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML, CSS, SASS, Npm, Java, Material UI React, React, ExpressJs, NodeJs, MongoDb, Mongoose, FlexBox, Grid, Jira, BootStrap, Git